<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Feature SiLA2Version="1.0" FeatureVersion="1.0" MaturityLevel="Draft" Originator="org.silastandard" Category="core"
         xmlns="http://www.sila-standard.org"
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.sila-standard.org https://gitlab.com/SiLA2/sila_base/raw/master/schema/FeatureDefinition.xsd">
  <Identifier>ErrorRecoveryService</Identifier>
  <DisplayName>Error Recovery Service</DisplayName>
  <Description>
    This feature enables SiLA error handling during the execution of observable commands.
    A client can subscribe to the property 'RecoverableErrors' which contains a list of recoverable errors that occurred and are not
    handled yet.
    If a recoverable error occurs during the execution of an observable command, a respective error object will be added to the list of
    the property 'RecoverableErrors'. Each error object contains the error description, the CommandExecutionUUID of the observable command
    execution during which the error occurred and a list of possible continuation options.
    To handle the error, the client sends one of the provided continuation options together with the commandExecutionUUID, using the
    command 'ExecuteContinuationOption'. Optionally the client can send additional data that might be required to execute a certain
    continuation option, e.g. an adjusted parameter value.
    When the server receives the continuation option the according error object will be removed from the list of the property
    'RecoverableErrors'.
    In case of multi client access it is recommended that only one client (preferably the one that issued the according command execution)
    handles recoverable errors.
  </Description>

  <Property>
    <Identifier>RecoverableErrors</Identifier>
    <DisplayName>Recoverable Errors</DisplayName>
    <Description>A list of all recoverable errors that occurred during execution and have not been handled yet.</Description>
    <Observable>Yes</Observable>
    <DataType>
      <List>
        <DataType>
          <DataTypeIdentifier>RecoverableError</DataTypeIdentifier>
        </DataType>
      </List>
    </DataType>
  </Property>

  <Command>
    <Identifier>ExecuteContinuationOption</Identifier>
    <DisplayName>Execute Continuation Option</DisplayName>
    <Description>Executes the selected option to recover the error.</Description>
    <Observable>No</Observable>
    <Parameter>
      <Identifier>CommandExecutionUUID</Identifier>
      <DisplayName>CommandExecutionUUID</DisplayName>
      <Description>The UUID of the observable command execution for which the error shall be handled.</Description>
      <DataType>
        <Basic>String</Basic>
      </DataType>
    </Parameter>
    <Parameter>
      <Identifier>ContinuationOption</Identifier>
      <DisplayName>Continuation Option</DisplayName>
      <Description>
        The identifier of the continuation option to be executed. It must match the identifier of one of the continuation options
        specified in the 'ContinuationOptions' list of the according 'RecoverableError' object.
      </Description>
      <DataType>
        <Basic>String</Basic>
      </DataType>
    </Parameter>
    <Parameter>
      <Identifier>AdditionalData</Identifier>
      <DisplayName>Additional Data</DisplayName>
      <Description>
        This parameter can contain data which has to be sent along with a continuation option in order to execute the requested recovery
        option. The kind of the data as well as the required format must be described in the respective continuation option description.
      </Description>
      <DataType>
        <Basic>String</Basic>
      </DataType>
    </Parameter>
    <DefinedExecutionErrors>
      <Identifier>InvalidCommandExecutionUUID</Identifier>
      <Identifier>UnknownContinuationOption</Identifier>
    </DefinedExecutionErrors>
  </Command>

  <DataTypeDefinition>
    <Identifier>RecoverableError</Identifier>
    <DisplayName>Recoverable Error</DisplayName>
    <Description>
      Describes an error that can be recovered by error handling. It contains error information (such as the command execution during
      which the error occurred, the time when the error occurred and the description of the error situation) and a list of possible
      continuation options.
      One of the continuation options can be marked as default option. A timeout can be specified for the automatic execution of
      that option if the client doesn't send a continuation option during the specified duration.
    </Description>
    <DataType>
      <Structure>
        <Element>
          <Identifier>CommandIdentifier</Identifier>
          <DisplayName>Command Identifier</DisplayName>
          <Description>The fully qualified identifier of the command whose execution produced the error.</Description>
          <DataType>
            <Constrained>
              <DataType>
                <Basic>String</Basic>
              </DataType>
              <Constraints>
                <FullyQualifiedIdentifier>CommandIdentifier</FullyQualifiedIdentifier>
              </Constraints>
            </Constrained>
          </DataType>
        </Element>
        <Element>
          <Identifier>CommandExecutionUUID</Identifier>
          <DisplayName>CommandExecutionUUID</DisplayName>
          <Description>The UUID of the observable command execution during which the error occured.</Description>
          <DataType>
            <Basic>String</Basic>
          </DataType>
        </Element>
        <Element>
          <Identifier>ErrorMessage</Identifier>
          <DisplayName>Error Message</DisplayName>
          <Description>
            This message describes the error situation. It should contain the reason of the error and additional error handling
            explanation.
          </Description>
          <DataType>
            <Basic>String</Basic>
          </DataType>
        </Element>
        <Element>
          <Identifier>ContinuationOptions</Identifier>
          <DisplayName>Continuation Options</DisplayName>
          <Description>A list of possible options to recover the error and continue the command execution.</Description>
          <DataType>
            <List>
              <DataType>
                <DataTypeIdentifier>ContinuationOption</DataTypeIdentifier>
              </DataType>
            </List>
          </DataType>
        </Element>
        <Element>
          <Identifier>DefaultOption</Identifier>
          <DisplayName>Default Option</DisplayName>
          <Description>
            The identifier of a continuation option that is marked as the preferred option. It must be an identifier of one of the
            continuation options of the 'ContinuationOptions' list.
            It can also be defined to be automatically executed after a timeout specified by the 'AutomaticExecutionTimeout' element.
          </Description>
          <DataType>
            <Basic>String</Basic>
          </DataType>
        </Element>
        <Element>
          <Identifier>AutomaticExecutionTimeout</Identifier>
          <DisplayName>Automatic Execution Timeout</DisplayName>
          <Description>
            Specifies a timeout (in seconds) for handling the error by the client. If the client does not send a continuation option
            within the specified duration, the defined default option will automatically be executed.
            A value of -1 means, that no automatic execution will be done by the server.
            This timeout only takes effect if a default option is specified, otherwise it will be ignored.
          </Description>
          <DataType>
            <Constrained>
              <DataType>
                <Basic>Integer</Basic>
              </DataType>
              <Constraints>
                <MinimalInclusive>-1</MinimalInclusive>
              </Constraints>
            </Constrained>
          </DataType>
        </Element>
      </Structure>
    </DataType>
  </DataTypeDefinition>

  <DataTypeDefinition>
    <Identifier>ContinuationOption</Identifier>
    <DisplayName>Continuation Option</DisplayName>
    <Description>Describes a possible option to recover an occurred error.</Description>
    <DataType>
      <Structure>
        <Element>
          <Identifier>Identifier</Identifier>
          <DisplayName>Identifier</DisplayName>
          <Description>The identifier of the continuation option. It must be unique within the RecoverableError object.</Description>
          <DataType>
            <Basic>String</Basic>
          </DataType>
        </Element>
        <Element>
          <Identifier>Description</Identifier>
          <DisplayName>Description</DisplayName>
          <Description>
            A human readable text describing the continuation option. It must explain all required manual actions by the operator
            as well as the actions that will be executed by the server and the expectable results when this option is selected.
            If there is additional data that can be sent along with the continuation option, the kind of the data as well as the
            required format must be described as well.
          </Description>
          <DataType>
            <Basic>String</Basic>
          </DataType>
        </Element>
      </Structure>
    </DataType>
  </DataTypeDefinition>

  <DefinedExecutionError>
    <Identifier>InvalidCommandExecutionUUID</Identifier>
    <DisplayName>Invalid Command Execution UUID</DisplayName>
    <Description>
      The specified command execution UUID is not valid for error recovery. There is currently no unhandled recoverable error related
      to the specified command execution. A possibly occurred error might have been handled already by another client.
    </Description>
  </DefinedExecutionError>

  <DefinedExecutionError>
    <Identifier>UnknownContinuationOption</Identifier>
    <DisplayName>Unknown Continuation Option</DisplayName>
    <Description>The specified continuation option is not defined for the given recoverable error.</Description>
  </DefinedExecutionError>
</Feature>
